The Gruffalo is a animation, family film directed by Max Lang.
The magical tale of a mouse who sets foot on a
woodland adventure in search of a nut.
Encountering predators who all wish to eat him - Fox, Owl and Snake - the brave
mouse creates a terrifying, imaginary monster to frighten them away.
But what will the mouse do when he meets this frightful monster for real?
Mother Squirrel (voice), played by Helena Bonham Carter.
Snake (voice), played by Rob Brydon.
The Gruffalo (voice), played by Robbie Coltrane.
Mouse (voice), played by James Corden.
Owl (voice), played by John Hurt.
Fox (voice), played by Tom Wilkinson.
The Gruffalo is a 2009 animated fantasy short television film based on the 1999
picture book written by Julia Donaldson and illustrated by Axel Scheffler.
Directed by Jakob Schuh and Max Lang, the film was produced by Michael Rose and Martin Pope of Magic Light Pictures and Orange Eyes Limited in association
with the award-winning Studio Soi in Ludwigsburg who developed and created the film., and produced in association with the BBC, Nick Jr.
The cast includes Helena Bonham Carter, Rob Brydon, James Corden,
Robbie Coltrane, John Hurt, and Tom Wilkinson.
9.8 million people watched the UK premiere on BBC One, Friday 25 December 2009 and the
film went on to receive nominations for both an Academy Award
and a BAFTA.
It was screened in US theatres, distributed by Kidtoon Films.
In December 2012, the film and its sequel The Gruffalo's Child premiered on television in the United States on Disney Junior, and in
December 2017 – 2018, the film and its sequel premiered on television in the United States on the Disney Junior channel.
The film explores themes of based on children's book, cartoon
mouse, short film, cartoon fox, cartoon snake.